They're brother and sister.
Shaun, Emma and Phoebe are on a special assignment.
They have left South Africa and travelled 1,000 miles north-west to Namibia.
They're off to meet an old friend, flying vet, Mark Jago.
He's a big cat expert with 19 years of African wildlife experience.
Mark has asked Emma and Shaun to help him on a very important conservation project - tracking and testing some of the world's wildest lions here in Etosha National Park.
Park warden Shayne Kotting is co-ordinating the project.
It's a massive park.
It's 2.2 million hectares.
We've been tracking lions since last week, trying to keep an eye where they are.
We've had very good success on the 19th latitude, here.
We managed to find a few prides.
Unfortunately, over the weekend, as Murphy would have it, we've lost all the animals because we've had rain.
So all the prides have dispersed at the moment.
So now we must be very opportunistic.
If we spot lions, if we hear about lions, we go and investigate.
If it's a doable pride, we go ahead and do it.
So we're looking at day and night darting?
Daytime, night time, whenever we can find them.
When you think how much we battle, in say 40,000 hectares, to take 1,000 animals off, we're now looking at 30 on 2.2 million hectares.
This is a huge challenge.
A lion in a haystack.
Etosha National Park is the third biggest game park in Africa.
It's the size of Wales.
To find lions here, Shaun and Mark must first take to the air.
We've got something down there.
On your left, on the ground?
We've got a pride of what looks like four or five below us.
About 20 nautical miles to the west of...
They've spotted a pride, but getting close to them on the ground will require all of Shaun's tracking skills.
Phoebe's come to help.
It's all relatively fresh spoor, but it's all springbok.
No lion.
The problem we've got here is, trying to pick up spoor from the ground is basically impossible.
The ground has been baked so hard nothing dents it.
Especially the soft pad of a lion.
Very difficult to pick up on the grass.
This is a very special population of lions - the Etosha lions.
Apart from being notoriously aggressive, which worries me slightly, they are also special in the way that they're all what we call relatively clean from diseases.
One of the most important diseases is the FIV virus, which sounds like HIV because it is.
It's the immuno-deficiency virus that is specific for cats.
This is a very special project now to try and test them for the FIV virus.
What we're doing at the moment is driving up to all the big thickets where there's lots of shade where we know the lions will lie up during the midday heat.
Two nice big males.
Brilliant, we'll get Marcus out.
Then we can continue.
Two hours looking and...
With the lions located, Shaun can call in Emma and the rest of the veterinary team.
The Etosha lions rarely come into contact with humans.
Their isolation means they are uniquely disease-free.
It also means they're especially dangerous.
With a lot of the reserves we work on with lions, they're very habituated to humans.
It makes the capture much easier and they're very used to vehicles driving in.
These boys, apparently, aren't that used to vehicles and this is their pad.
We're trespassing.
All right?
Yes.
Stop...
Stop.
Lions are incredibly dangerous and it's one of the species that we won't allow her to come out at all especially as a couple of lions in this area are renowned for being particularly aggressive.
One of the possibilities is that the lions take a dislike to us and jump on the back of the bukkie.
An open bukkie.
We're crouching down here because the lions are used to a particular silhouette of a vehicle.
If we stand up that could really piss them off.
We don't want a pissed off lion.
Did I get him?
Can you see the dart?
It sounded like a hit.
The dart just dropped a little bit.
We've just got to make sure that's a hit.
We're just letting him move off.
The second lion has moved away, but the team must wait for the darted lion to go down.
It is frustrating.
You want to be out there getting your hands dirty.
As long as she doesn't have any pooey nappies we should get away with it.
Air conditioner.
It's all very well seeing an animal that looks unconscious - it doesn't mean he is unconscious.
OK.
Do you want some gloves?
Yes, please.
Is that a towel for his eyes there?
That's a towel for his eyes.
Thank you.
While the animal's down, everybody's dived in to do as many procedures as possible.
Measurements, blood samples, tick removals, Measurements, blood samples, tick removals, praying mantis removal...
Praying mantis.
He's a young adult.
OK, this is a pulse oximeter.
This is a great toy, especially when you're doing this sort of thing in the field.
It tells me the pulse rate and also his oxygen saturation as well, which is important.
You see the blood tube filling up there nicely now.
Just look at those teeth.
You can see the size of these claws.
They could do a huge amount of damage.
He's in fantastic condition.
He's got lovely muscles.
He obviously works for his food.
What I'm trying to do is collect a fresh faecal sample.
We're trying to find out if they're carrying parasites, any form of internal parasites.
It's not everybody has the opportunity to do such a wonderful thing as put their hand up the back end of a lion.
OK, just giving him the reversal.
It can vary according to the individual how long, but in 15-20 minutes he might start lifting up his head and then he'll become more with it.
We should get on the bukkie in case...
It's not 15-20 minutes.
It's five minutes.
For the test results to be meaningful, the team must find 30 lions.
They need another 29.
But the project has temporarily been put on hold.
Emma, Shaun and Mark have had an urgent call from Africat, a cheetah sanctuary.
This morning one of their animals has been found dead.
It's the second cheetah to die in six weeks.
Dave Houghton, who helps run the sanctuary, needs to find out what's killing his cheetahs.
To solve the mystery, Emma and Mark are going to perform an autopsy on the dead male.
This is Moe.
As you can smell, it's been a bit of a while.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Got him.
Dave, when did you find him?
He was found this morning but I don't actually know how long he's been dead.
Maggots already in.
But small maggots.
This is quite foul.
You can see what Mark's able to do now, he can pull the fur without any problems.
Obviously, there's a big area of infection around here because if I try and pull the fur up here it's absolutely firm.
This is very sad.
He's been here for nearly eight years.
A lovely success story, hunting for himself, hunting really well.
Something maybe bigger and better got him.
Cheetahs tend to go for plains game.
They can have horns and can fight back and that's a possibility - the cheetah could have got injured by the prey.
Let's just turn him over and have a look on the other side.
OK, there's another couple of holes here.
It's all in the same area.
A single oryx horn is not gonna produce that kind of injury.
You've got one, two, three, four...
I mean, they are tear wounds as much as puncture wounds.
Look at that.
You can see the clean, healthy tissue and there's all the infected wound.
It looks like, more than likely, another predator.
A bigger predator has grabbed hold of him, and carnivores have awful bacteria, same as domestic cats.
I've had most of my damage from domestic cats.
They've got rotten bacteria and the infection has gone really deep inside the tissue there.
The most likely predator is a leopard.
I mean, we've certainly seen the leopard attacking in the past a cheetah when it's been on a kill.
Under normal circumstances a cheetah could actually run away, or possibly would run away.
You've got to remembered these are rehabilitated cheetahs, they have not got all their natural instinct.
Moe was one of four orphans learning how to fend for themselves in one of Africat's huge rehab enclosures.
Now there are just two left.
Ideally, we're best to catch the leopard.
The problem is they're not easy animals to catch.
Box traps take time and to go on foot is difficult and dangerous.
So we're gonna take out the two cheetahs in here.
Emma's been doing all the predator darting at the moment so I'm quite chuffed with the opportunity to go and dart.
Darting the world's fastest land mammal is a chance for Shaun to show off his marksmanship.
But these are not your typical cheetahs.
WHISTLES This is Artemis and Apollo.
They're brother and sister.
I don't think I've ever been this close to something to dart.
Hey, my girl, you're next.
I could have got a cheetah closer to him so he could have stuck a syringe in but I thought he was close enough.
And I nearly missed!
It's such a unique opportunity to actually dart an animal.
You can call it back so it's not gonna run off and go missing.
In fact, I went to find them a couple of months ago when they were looking really thin.
I had to go in the bush a bit.
It got so thick I just whistled and eventually they came, but they ran straight past me and they were waiting at the car when I got back to the car.
It's such a pity that we've got to take them out of the camp but it's the safest thing for the cheetah.
Have you ever walked with them when they're going out on a hunt?
I haven't, no.
They normally go quite quick.
That was quite a stupid question, wasn't it?
It was very stupid, but there you go.
He's getting wobbly now, he'll go down any second.
Teaching any young orphan to survive in the wild is incredibly difficult, especially with cheetahs like Artemis and Apollo.
They have come to us when they're young cubs.
They haven't had their mothers' experience.
They're lacking in life skills.
They don't know that when a leopard comes up they must run away.
They're trying to defend their kill when they shouldn't be.
There's a new arrival at the sanctuary - four orphaned warthogs.
Dave's partner Carla has asked Emma to sort out the girls from the boys.
Look at you!
How on earth did you get these little things?
The people who found them think their mother was attacked by something.
They had to, unfortunately, put the mother down, so they had to be hand-reared.
And have you got some tusks starting up?
That's the most dangerous bit about you lot.
You look cute, but you can be trouble.
Especially if they don't have any fear of humans, which these obviously don't at the moment.
That's the one thing that our guys all run away from, is a warthog!
And they also squeal to high heaven!
And they don't like being picked up!
Are you chewing my boot there?
But they look in really good condition.
We've definitely got a male there.
The males have two warts there.
I don't know if you can see on him there.
I need to see your bottom.
Little girl there.
And that's another little girl, isn't it?
Yeah, girl.
So he's easy to identify, but how are you gonna tell the difference?
This job requires a feminine touch.
Do you have a colour preference?
That one's probably better, it's a bit lighter.
Which leg?
Well done, little one!
There we go.
It's all right.
Little warthog manicure for you as well.
All done.
That's it, off you go.
She's even walking like a lady now.
They look like they're walking on high heels.
They do, don't they?
They're beautiful little things.
Bye-bye!
While Artemis and Apollo are still under sedation, Mark wants to give them a quick check-up.
Just gonna make sure the rest of them are all right.
These cheetahs may look tame, but they are not pets.
If threatened, they'll attack.
Stand by, stand by.
Yeah.
Hold on.
Good drama for you!
Artemis and Apollo will be looked after in a temporary enclosure until the leopard is caught.
It's a long way from the wild, but at least they'll be safe.
OK!
Enjoy your stay.
Nice little holiday.
Welcome to Okajima Holiday Camp.
In the future, if they're to survive, these orphans must learn when to fight and when to take flight.
Two weeks later, their most immediate threat, the rogue leopard, was caught and relocated.
Phoebe, look!
A big chongololo.
Huge!
Wow, Pheebs!
How many legs has it got?
Two...
Six.
Six?
Really?
And they're coming.
Coming!
Hi!
Look at all these legs.
Lots of legs.
He's got more than six, hasn't he?
Big congolo.
Big chongololo.
Coming!
Wow!
Look at the legs, Pheebs.
Bye-bye, Mr Chongololo.
Back in Etosha, the temperature is rising.
It's over 40 degrees Celsius.
Shaun and Shayne are back out tracking lions.
Finally!
That's a big female.
Yeah.
Looks like a female.
Pretty much the only soft piece of soil on Etosha.
Lots of activity around here.
Quite a lot of small ones.
A couple of cubs, at least.
There's one set going that way.
There's another set over there.
That's at least two cubs.
What's that over there?
Ah!
That looks like it there.
We've managed to find some lions, a female and a couple of cubs.
So what we'll probably do is get the team and come and do these this afternoon.
It's too hot for the lions to be darted straight away, so everyone takes the chance to relax until things cool down.
Pretty dresses!
There's lots of down time, and it's very boring to catch up on gossip.
And sometimes you can't be fussy with what you're reading.
But the pictures are great, aren't they?
Gotta just check that you have a full education.
Gotta see the latest in fashion, got to keep up with fashion in the bush(!)
As long as it's khaki.
Shaun thinks these sort of magazines are absolutely awful, so I always find him reading them.
Did you say "complete waste of money"?
When the heat finally wanes, the team set off again.
As we're standing here, how many do they think are in there?
It looks as though there could be as many as ten.
They're gonna be a mixture of females and youngsters of various ages.
The females could be four or five, and the rest of them will be juveniles, probably.
I don't think we've seen a male.
Here you are.
Let's go.
There are five lionesses.
20 metres.
Good.
Well done.
A lucky shot, there.
OK, let's just give them two seconds.
No, stop, stop, stop!
Stop!
She's facing that way.
There's another one somewhere.
There she is.
She's just chewing it down.
They've hit four, but the fifth has gone missing.
You're starting to get sleepy.
Where's that other big female?
This is actually quite scary, because we've been told there's five adults here.
We've done four.
We can't spot the fifth one, so we're really reluctant to get off the bukkie until we spot that fifth one.
There are cubs involved here - the most beautiful little cubs - and this usually doesn't affect them, we're processing the mums very quickly.
It's a nice cross-section of this pride here.
But this is what the discussion is behind me.
Just keep an eye open.
I don't know where it is.
I can't see it.
Get your gun ready.
The last lioness can't be seen, but with night falling, the team must get started.
What we want to do is try and get the animals together, because that's the best way we can control the situation.
I'm checking these anaesthetics - I won't be able to do it if I'm running along.
I don't want to do it if I know there's another female out there who's not been darted.
The cubs are staying close to their sedated mothers.
They don't represent a risk, but the solitary female does.
Now the challenge begins.
I'm keeping them anaesthetised long enough for all the procedures to be undertaken.
See the reflex there.
A bit of cream.
I'm trying to concentrate, but when you look behind and see the sunset, you realise what a beautiful place Etosha is.
I'm trying to ignore that.
Can we get some light, guys?
Apart from getting dark, we've got the storms coming in, as well!
So we're really working on a very tight schedule here.
As the sun sets quickly over Namibia, now is the time predators are most active.
I just hope someone here is looking out for the fifth female, which is cruising around behind us.
Because if she comes too close to us, people are gonna start running fairly quickly.
Right, let's start branding them.
Mark?
The branding will enable the team to match up the test results with each lion.
All he's doing is just burning just the top part of the skin.
He's not going too deep.
As you can see, the animal's not flinching at all, which means I don't need to top her up.
Very nervous now.
The animals have been under for quite a while.
We're just finishing them off.
We wanna make sure they don't wake up.
It's exceedingly dangerous - we have an adult, free-ranging lion.
Guys, look at that storm.
Let's have rain as well.
Nice.
The fifth lioness has been spotted.
She's only 100 yards from the team.
All the darts are out.
I need some muscle power.
Drag.
One, two, three, drag.
OK, that's fine.
No.
No, leave that one, she's waking up.
Everybody ready to move her?
Let's move off a bit, then we can watch them from a distance.
The lioness is getting closer.
It's time for a swift exit.
See the youngsters coming back just to check on their mums.
The lionesses are recovering and the cubs are safe.
Five down, 25 to go.
Next week - the lions fight back.
I've got spoors.
Shaun tracks one of the most elusive of wild carnivores.
And he's not very asleep, so just let it down.
And Phoebe celebrates a big day.